Bilal Ul Haque

Web Developer

+92 (345) 2156788

in linkedin.com/in/bilal-ul-haque/

github.com/bilalulhaque

Summary

An energetic, competent, and enthusiastic learner with a thorough understanding of frontend frameworks, backend technology and, design tools. 2+ years of professional expertise in the areas of solution design and development. Python, open-source technologies, JS, SQL, NOSQL, and Docker are among my moderate skills. I'm looking to strengthen my skills under the supervision of senior developers.

Work experience

Web Developer

Nov 2020 - Current

Freelancer

• 15+ prospective projects were successfully completed and delivered on time with a 5-star rating.

Internee July 2020 - Oct 2020

NASH

• Worked on Rest API using AJAX fetching techniques and implemented different wire-frames designs on web apps using HTML/CSS/JS

Technical Skills

• Languages/Frameworks: Python, PHP, Django, Flask, Node JS

• Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

• Web Client-Side Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS

• Databases: MYSQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL

• **Docker**(beginner)

• Version Control tools: GIT

Education

2018 - 2022

NED University of Engineering and Technology

Intermediate (Pre Engineering)

2016 - 2018

Jinnah Government College

Matriculation

2014 - 2016

Ladybird Grammar School

Certification

- Linux Essentials Certificate
- Data Science in Python by University of MICHIGAN
- HTML, CSS and Javascript for Web Developers by John Hopkins University
- CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript

Final Year Project

Urdu Speech To Text

Supervised by Furgan Hussain Essani

Users can transform any Urdu lecture into an English-subtitled lecture using this software. With the use of phonemes, an Automated Speech Recognition (ASR) system turns audio into a series of related words. It models the link between audio signal and phonetic units using an acoustic model based on Deep Neural Networks (DNN). The implementation is accompanied by research.

Projects

TestGorilla Feb 2022

Created scenario-based interview questions for Flask.

Movies Info Site Nov 2021

A small web app where the admin posts description and trailer about the movies released every year. User can view all of these without any registration.

My Group Solutions - Membership Monitoring

Aug 2021

A web application for an organization in which the administrator can develop activities for their members, update their records on a regular basis, and keep track of many users.

FotoDino - Baby Shooting Website

April 2021

An application where users can book photograph sessions for their child. Implemented front-end and worked on Restful API using Axios.

Student Portal System

Feb 2021

A web application which facilitates teachers and students. Teachers can update students attendance and marks. The students can view their attendance, marks and can manage their profile.

Shopify Sneaker Bot

Dec 2020

A bot to automatically buy products from the specified website at small intervals. Technologies used are **Python Selenium**.

Nixu Awareness Portal - LMS

Nov 2020

A web application that raises user awareness. Admins can view the performance of their users using charts and graphs.

Lets Chit Chat Oct 2020

An application implemented on website where users can login through different authentication methods and can communicate.

Extra Curricular activities

- Member of Champions of Change 'Bazm-e-Aman', 2021
- Member of 19th ITCN Asia Exhibition, 2019
- Participated in HVACR and Building Services Expo Conference, 2019
- Participated in Google Hash Code, 2022